Correcting the daily journal.
Now in the beginning when children start writing on their own of course you want to encourage creativity and some people feel that correcting every little thing they do wrong is going to snub their creativity and make them frustrated.
I don't think that's necessarily true but I think in the beginning it is fun to let them write however they right and to save the journals and they can look back on it even a year later and laugh and say look at how I used to write, it's so neat and you can save it, it's so nostalgic.
But, at some point you want to start correcting them and as soon as they ask you, you want to give them a correction so in this case, the child wrote wun the way it should be written phonetically but that's not the correct way so if they ask you how do I write it?
You can say, you can tell them, and when you're ready to start correcting their journals, like I said, you don't have to do it in the first few but after a while, you can start correcting them.
What you do is, you underwrite underneath and you would write the correct way in a different color, one time, and you know, praise them on all the words that they wrote correctly and then show them, talk about why that's spelled a little differently than they thought.
To the, one time I went to the store and remember silent e, you know, tell them about each thing and, I got a jug of milk.
Almost perfect.
And that's how you can correct.
Now sometimes you can even have them write the whole thing over again but that kind of ruins the fun in this case because it's a journal but other times when you have them practice writing and then you correct their writing, it's not a bad idea to have them say, now write this whole thing over with the corrections put in.
And that more reinforces in their mind the correct way to write things.